Ingrid Fuentes

917-620-4558 | ingridfmelgar@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>Blogs</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer with working knowledge of Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React/Redux based programming. Familiar with Data Structures. Background in business administration with experience in account management. Fluent in Spanish, Catalan, and Italian. Developed an Interview Tracker, which helped me grow my programming skills, and the ability to leverage my full-stack knowledge to build an interactive and user-centered website.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, PostgreSQL, RESTful, APIs, Bootstrap, Firebase, Cloud Firestore. Object-oriented programming. I'm excited to learn new technologies.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Interview Tracker - Github | Demo

I created a single page React web app with a Rails API for individuals who want to keep track of their job applications

- App built with Rails as a backend and JavaScript, React.js and Redux as front-end. Used sessions to store user's data
- PostgreSQL as a database
- Bootstrap, HTML, CSS to style the website

Choco Gourmet- Chocolate Store - Github | Demo

Chocolate store where a user can buy their favorite chocolates online

- Used rails as a backend and vanilla JavaScript. Also, HTML, CSS
- SQLite to keep track of data
- Utilized localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

Sabores del Mundo-Recipe Finder - Github | Demo

Recipe finder. A user can find other user's recipes and can create their own recipes

- App built with Rails. RESTful API for users to save their recipes. Utilized BCRYPT to store encrypted user information for security
- Database using SQLite
- Added HTML and CSS

University of North America

Master's degree in Computer Science

EDUCATION

| Flatiron School Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program | New York City, NY 06/2019 - 05/2020 |
|--|--|
| University of Barcelona Bachelor in Business Administration | Barcelona, Spain 02/2009 - 06/2014 |

EXPERIENCE

OPEN WATER ACCELERATOR

New York, USA 09/2020 - 12/2020

Fairfax. VA

01/2021

Software Engineer Intern

- Web development. Front-end using Javascript and React is
- Work closely with the Front-end team to make sure the user's experience is efficient
- Coordinate with the team to make the work on time in an efficient way and keep the code clean

ATC TORREALDAY

Barcelona, Spain
Accounting Associate

09/2013 - 08/2015

- Prepared invoices, managed clients accounts, and prepared reports for firm Accountants
- Communicated with clients via email and phone to handle account-related requests
- Clarified accounting issues with auditors and account managers